

Phani Teja KAMBHAMPATI

"Be the change you wish to see in the world"
- Gandhi

+91 9866512965 National Renewable Energy Internship phaniteja1@gmail.com
Iinkedin.com/in/phani-teja/

National Renewable Energy Internship MNRE – Govt. Of India

MISSION

Master in Energy Management at ESCP EUROPE. Aims to contribute in mitigating the challenges for Clean Energy Transition of Indian Energy Sector and Clean Energy Economy.

Six years of IT Consulting experience in IT Process & Operations Management, Technology Cost Management and Business Analytics. Holds entrepreneurial experience in three consumer goods sectors. Available Immediately.

EDUCATION

2018-2020 ESCP EUROPE BUSINESS SCHOOL, PARIS

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN ENERGY MANAGEMENT

Thesis: Challenges for Energy Transition in the Indian consumer market

Relevant Coursework:

Electricity & Renewable Markets; Energy Trading; Oil & Gas Business; Energy Policy; Energy Markets &

Commodities; Energy Security & International Politics; R&D and Innovation in Energy Business;

2008-2012 JN TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY, HYDERABAD

India

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2017-2018 UNITED HEALTH GROUP, USA | SENIOR BUSINESS ANALYST

India

Technology Cost Management | Business Analytics

- Spearheaded the Technology Cost Management (TCM) initiative on behalf of Office of CIO
- Formulated methods for IT cost optimization, resulted in annualized savings of \$5M USD
- Resolved cost leaks worth \$6.9M USD/year through IT chargebacks

2012-2017 HCL TECHNOLOGIES LTD | SENIOR SPECIALIST - ITIL PROCESS MANAGER

India

IT Infrastructure Operations | ITSM Data Analytics | ITIL Process Management

- Led strategic process reviews with C-Level executives and stakeholders. Oversaw service improvements
- Deployed ITSM analytical solutions for major incident, problem and IT capacity management processes
- Directed several IT war rooms during major IT service disruptions for timely restoration of service

VOLUNTEERING

2011-2013	INDIAN YOUTH CLIMATE NETWORK PROJECT COORDINATOR	India		
	Energy & Carbon Audit: Led the audit for partnered institutions such as Hospitals, Schools & Hotels			
START-UP PROJECTS				
2018-2019	NIJI DESIGN STUDIO Fashion	India		
	Digital Marketing: Enabled the digital marketing platform and oversaw brand's outreach			
	Operations: Managed the operations within the supply chain network			
2017-2018	PEPUP Food & Beverages	India		
	• Investor: Managed the capital funds and cashflow accurately, resulted in net growth			
	• Operations: Streamlined end to end operations by reducing the complexity in the supply chain			
2017-2018	FEGO INNOVATIONS Automotive accessories	India		
	Marketing & Sales: Facilitated the marketing campaign for the product launch			
	Product Design: Contributed in real-time product testing and design improvements			
TOOLS				

CERTIFICATIONS	IT TOOLS	LANGUAGES
	Microsoft Office: Excel, PowerPoint, Word	English: Bilingual
ITIL Intermediate: Service Operations	Bloomberg Terminal	Hindi: Bilingual
in IT Service Management, 2016	ITSM Tools: Service Now, BMC Remedy	Telugu: Native
	Data Viz: Tableau	Tamil: Elementary
		French: Elementary

INTERESTS

Date: 04-12-2019

Dear Officer,

I am Phani Teja, final year student of Master in Energy management at ESCP EUROPE Business School (London & Paris).

I am writing this letter expressing my interest to work under NREI scheme (6 months) at Ministry of New and Renewable Energy, Government of India.

I appreciate this internship opportunity as this would give me a grassroots level exposure in diverse Renewable Energy projects undertaken by the Ministry and it also enables me to contribute in achieving the some of the objectives of the program.

With the Passion to work in Renewable Energy Industry, after working for 6 years in IT industry, I am currently pursuing Masters in Energy Management, through which I have gained **insights about the International Renewable Energy Market and the Energy Transition** in the European Markets.

My thesis 'Challenges for clean energy transition in Indian market' is primarily focused on Rooftop Solar adaption in the Indian market. It has allowed me to gain insights about the various policies launched by MNRE and the impact it has created in the Solar Industry and by large, within the Indian Renewable Energy sector.

It would be an honour to be part of the MNRE and work for the distinguished officers. I believe I can contribute to the team by bringing the International perspective while also incorporating my business education and IT skills.

I'm currently in my final year of my master's program and **immediately available** to assume the responsibilities of Intern at any of the designated locations as assigned.

At MNRE, as an Intern, I would not only have a chance to apply my International Business Education coupled with my IT Consulting experience but also pursue my passion to contribute in the transition towards clean energy economy.

I look forward to interacting with you soon to discuss further about my experience and explore the contribution I could make at MNRE.

Thank you for your time and consideration.

Sincerely,

Phani Teja KAMBHAMPATI

MSc Energy Management

ESCP EUROPE Business School, Paris